Efren Marin

Los Angeles County | (562) 441-4544 | <u>efren45marin@gmail.com</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/efren-marin/</u> | <u>github.com/efrenmarin45</u> | <u>efrenmarin.com</u>

Summary

Full Stack Developer leveraging a strong background in finance and management with close to a decade in experience. Practical knowledge working with a MERN stack and with different frameworks and libraries.

Technical Skills

Front-end: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize, Handlebars.JS

Back-end: Node.JS, MySQL, NoSQL, Express, MongoDB

Complementing Tech: VS Code, Git, GitLab, PostMan, Terminal, MySQLWorkbench, Robo3T, Atlas

Projects

Internal Inventory System | http://bmf-inventory-management.herokuapp.com/

Tech: MongoDB, React, Express, Redux, Materialize, Node.js, Atlas

- Sourced a business client who needed an internal tool where they could store and update their inventory along with authentication for employees.
- Built out an authenticated internal tool that allows the user to input information about vendors and materials and also be able to pull the data from the database.
- I was responsible for the database, routes, and peer programmed React.

Developer Profile Generator | http://github.com/efrenmarin45/Developer-Profile-Generator
Tech: Node.js, HTML5, CSS3, and Javascript

- Working with GitHub API to dynamically produce an HTML page with the user's profile
- By following the CLI prompts, the user can generate an HTML page containing their GitHub stats and styled with their favorite color.

Employee Tracker | http://github.com/efrenmarin45/Employee-Tracker

Tech: Node.js, MySQL, and Javascript

- This program uses CRUD actions to manage an employee management database
- The user will be able to create employees, departments, and roles as well as view existing ones in the database. The user will also be able to maintain the database by updating or deleting the departments, employees, or roles using the CLI.

Code Quiz | https://efrenmarin45.github.io/CodeQuiz/

Tech: HTML5, CSS3, and Javascript

- This is a timed interactive quiz that tests the user's knowledge on CSS3, Javascript, and HTML5
- This program asks the user to help Harry, better understand some HTML, CSS, and Javascript questions by taking a timed quiz. As the user progresses through, any wrong answers will have a time penalty and any correct answers will award points.

Work Experience

Acorns Irvine, CA 2019-Present

Investor Success

- Assist investors with their accounts and provide technical support when needed
- Educate existing and new investors on our different accounts and features

Private Client Banker 2017-2019

- Successfully created and grew relationships with clients and small businesses in excess of \$10MM
- Led a financial literacy initiative and hosted seminars within my area to help my team grow their understanding of finance

Manager on Duty 2013-2019

- Moved into a leadership position and assisted in creating a strong productive work culture that resulted in substantial asset growth.
- Assisted in mentoring bank employees as well as helping to ensure that day to day operations for the branch ran as expected.

Personal/Relationship Banker 2011-2017

- Successfully established a pipeline of clients and assisted the immediate area with basic lending needs and financial planning.
- Collaborated to source new clients for business partners and investment advisors.

Education

UCLA Extension Westwood, CA 2019-2020

Full Stack Certificate

- Went through a rigorous course that covered the full MERN stack.
- Successfully deployed projects and completed client work via remote coding